Today we are driving the all-new 2026 Lexus ES 350h.
This is the premium front-wheel drive.
As tested, this is about $53,000.
We have the palomino interior, which looks very nice on here.
A little bit larger of an ES for the 2026 model year.
Of course, this is a fully redesigned inside and out.
It's available as an EV or as this 350h hybrid.
This is the front-wheel drive model.
You can also get the hybrid in all-wheel drive.
As specced, this gets about 48 miles per gallon on the highway, about 44 in the city, 46 combined,
which is an amazing fuel economy, 244 net combined horsepower, and a completely new
interior and exterior.
Let's walk you guys around it, talk about what it's been like to spend the first 30,
40 minutes behind the wheel of this car, and give you guys some first driving impressions.
Let's start off with this interior.
Very similar to the Lexus TZ that we did a walk-around of, or a tease of, a couple videos
ago.
So, we've got this massive 14-point-some-inch touchscreen.
It's very similar to what we've seen in the new Toyota RAV4, and I like that.
Except for the EV, Lexus ES, it has lots of route planning features, which is really nice
to see.
You've got a whole climate menu right here, but you have physical climate buttons right
here.
They're push-in, they're not haptic like they look like they are.
We've got a front defrost volume, physical button for your hazard switch, USB-C ports,
and then buttons down here for your parking brake, brake hold, EV mode, and traction off.
The Premium only comes with a reverse camera, though I think the Premium Plus has the 360
cam.
We have some really nice materials in this interior.
For just kind of being the base model, you've got this nice suede Alcantara piece right
next to the gauge cluster, the screens are bright, high-resolution, the graphics look
beautiful.
Definitely a step up for Lexus in terms of graphical display quality here, which I appreciate.
You have some quick access controls here to adjust brightness, which is great, though
that is only in the infotainment, not for all displays.
It should be for everything.
I don't know why Lexus always does that.
CarPlay is wireless, it's massive, you can see everything, all your apps all at once,
which is always a good thing.
And you've got some temperature control here, heated and ventilated seats, you can automatically
set those, heated steering wheel, and one wireless charge pad right here.
The center console opens up from both sides, and there is just an enormous amount of rear
seat room.
I'll talk outside and show you what this thing looks like.
It is a striking new design for Lexus.
This is painted in Iridium Silver, nice-looking color on this ES, a little bit of language
taken from the Camry, from the Prius, from a lot of Toyota's new models.
This has the standard 19-inch wheels, 19s are the only wheel option on the Hybrid, as
a jet flies over us.
Anyway, these are 235 and 55R19 Bridgestone Turanza EL450 tires, quiet, grippy, efficient,
you guys know the deal.
Take a look at the side profile.
Look at these new door handles, they actually work really well while maintaining some aerodynamic
advantages.
The rear view of this new ES is pretty striking, I like the roofline, the way it tapers down
into the trunk.
Now I have a Lexus text instead of a full-on Lexus badge.
All ES trunks are power-operated, and then there is just an enormous amount of trunk
space in the back of this.
Again, this package is both a Hybrid and an EV, you get tons of room in the back no matter
what you're running.
I'm just going to put the backpack here so it doesn't fly around during the review.
Press this button to close that trunk, look at that opening.
Taillights are pretty cool-looking, you've got that single strip in the back.
This will do almost 600 miles on a tank, so hybrid range here with the ES350h is fantastic.
We've got a couple USB ports back here and this premium vents, and that's kind of about
it.
Enormous amounts of legroom, look at this, this is just Lexus LS amounts of legroom back
here.
Nice materials, this is the new Luxe interior, got some cup holders, water bottle holders
right there.
Just a nice, open, spacious, airy interior.
Pretty low beltline with the windows.
I think this is a very nice place to be, it's very quiet in here too.
Of course you've got these same electronically operated door handles, you can pull them out
twice to manually operate them if something happens, but it's nice to just have these
that are easy to operate.
Pop the hood, take a look at this 2.5 liter naturally aspirated engine.
Lots of beeping and bonging, we have hood struts, look at that.
This all looks very well packaged, nicely presented here with the plastic engine cover,
and it's going to be enormously efficient.
This is Lexus' 6th generation hybrid system, it's smoother, it's quieter, it's more refined,
and it takes 0W8 engine oil, look at that.
Can't wait for 0W0 someday.
Check out these door handles, there's a little, it's an actual button that you pull inside
the handle.
Super easy to use, very satisfying.
More buttons right here that are kind of hidden and integrated nicely into the dashboard material.
3 seat memory settings, auto up/down windows for all four corners.
You've got a button right here to pop your trunk, your fuel filler cap, and then here's
your gauge cluster brightness, that's a physical switch.
So at least that's not hidden somewhere, thank you Lexus for giving us that.
It's a nice looking interior.
At first I was a big fan of this rubberized steering wheel material, but after using it
for about an hour, I'm not so sure.
It just feels kind of plasticky, but I guess it's okay.
It's super smooth, you've got nice paddle shifters behind the wheel, turn signal operation
feels really good here, and then we've got physical buttons for our cruise control, and
our track volume selection, all that stuff.
These lower buttons feel really nice in hand, they're kind of grippy and knurled, which
feels very good.
And then you've got a bunch of configurations here for your gauge clusters.
Of course you can customize this, variations on a theme from what we've seen from Lexus
and Toyota and their other cluster designs.
So you've got a nice EcoCharge power meter there.
I like this dual pod layout, it's pretty useful.
Let's delve into this infotainment system some.
So we've got our native navigation, you've got some different widgets here showing you
your music, your phone, your drive mode, and then you can customize all of this stuff,
which is great.
You can see your weather, your media, and then save all of that.
Very cool.
The climate menu doesn't really give you much more functionality, I guess you can customize
different things like S-Flow, de-icer, and then auto-adjust the seat temperature, but
most of your controls for temperature and fan speed are easily accessible right here.
Some of these icons are a little bit small, but you've got a little ridge underneath the
screen to rest and stabilize your hand, which I appreciate.
Of course, heated and ventilated seats, heated steering wheel, all that stuff, and then your
temperature control is right there.
Volume is a nice slider, and like I mentioned earlier, we only get a reverse camera in this
premium Lexus ES 350h.
Anything else I need to cover?
Here are the visors, they slide, we've got a big panoramic sunroof there, the seats are
nice and thin, but very well padded and comfortable, appreciate that.
You can hide your water bottle and cup holders with this, and there's a little bit of storage
underneath here, as well as some ambient lighting that you probably can't see too well during
the day right now.
Let's head out onto the road, we will enable our route, we've got a route to scan here,
and let's give you guys some first driving impressions on this new Lexus ES.
Doing Austin Powers four-point turn here, looks like we're going right, so we don't
need to wait ten minutes for this traffic light to turn.
The biggest thing you notice with this new ES is just how smooth and torquey it is.
Very little engine noise, very little NVH.
The ride is slightly firmer than I was expecting it to be, for what this car is, but once you
get up to speed, it seems really nicely damped, and really well isolated.
Good body control, it's a nice blend between sporting intentions but also good ride comfort.
Throttle response, even in normal mode, is pretty instant, and overall power feels great.
Brake pedal calibration, linear, responsive, none of that hybrid squish that sometimes
we get in Toyota and Lexus hybrids.
Everything just feels a little bit tighter, a little bit better calibrated in this new
ES.
And I feel like even though this is a pretty basic, simple interior, it's functional enough,
the stuff that is in the screen is easily and quickly accessible, and the materials
feel like an improvement over what Lexus has maybe been giving us over the last couple
years in some of their new products.
No shakes, no rattles, very little wind noise in this new ES, 44 horsepower for getting
in front of the Prius.
Alright.
It also feels surprisingly light and nimble on its feet, agile, I have good visibility.
If you want the full summary, it's a perfectly fine automobile.
I don't think it's outrageously priced, I could do with some premium plus features in
this.
Now the EV has a luxury trim, but you save a little bit of money with the EV too, trim
to trim.
This is about $2,000 going with the EV.
Of course you could always get this in all-wheel drive if you need it, but this has great traction
in the drive as a front-wheel drive platform.
First time Lexus is ever offering the ES as an all-wheel drive configuration.
I mean, they have the powertrains, why not swap them in?
It's kind of a surprise seeing Toyota add so many EV options to the lineup, it's basically
just the same packs that we've seen with the BZs, and they're just putting them in a bunch
of different models.
But the luxury ES has a lot more features, it's got lounge chairs in the back.
But if you just want a Lexus ES, the bare necessity, the bare-bones experience that
gives you the luxurious feel and the look, this ES 350h I think is probably going to
be the way to go.
It's got tons and tons of driving range as a hybrid, super fuel-efficient, very comfortable.
I think it kind of hits the nail on the head and does what you need it to do.
Really, the only thing I feel like I'm lacking in here is the Mark Levinson sound and a 360
cam, and you can option those things.
Let's do a sound system test with our standard sound system here, and see what that's like.
Volume controls here to the left, we're going to get a left lane on some of this traffic.
Still very clear.
Honestly, first impressions, this premium/base model sound system sounds great.
I mean, they're still calling the base model a premium, and then you can upgrade to the
premium plus with the hybrid, and you get the EV if you want to get into luxury, etc.
Maybe not as sweet as the Mark Levinson would be.
I haven't listened to the Mark Levinson yet, but this is great.
For $53,000, this is a fantastic sound system.
I also feel like this is a really nice interior direction for a Lexus.
I like the functionality, I like the layout and organization of everything.
It's just easy to acclimate to and easy to use.
I jumped into this car and immediately had an idea of where everything should be, and
even in the infotainment where stuff could be buried a little bit deeper here and there,
I felt like I had a good grasp on where different settings should be.
They pretty much moved a lot of the settings into here, instead of splitting them up between
the screen and the gauge cluster, which I appreciate.
I don't really have any complaints about this interior space.
I think it does exactly what it needs to do for the Lexus ES.
It's the exterior design that might be a point of contention for some buyers, whether they're
kind of into the swooping lines and crazy hard surfaces and all the things that Lexus
has done with their new design language.
I think people will ultimately get used to it.
We always do.
It's a pretty striking car to look at on first impressions, and it might turn off a few buyers
who want something a bit more sedate and subdued, which is understandable.
On a pretty bumpy section of road here, NVH is good.
Again, it's just a couple bumps are a bit more harsh than I was expecting with this
ES.
It's not as Lexus soft as I wanted it to be.
Driving around the city, it's super comfy.
You've got throttle control is nice and linear, no complaints there.
It'll remain in EV mode pretty readily at lower speeds, that transition from EV to internal
combustion engine turning on is seamless, it's silent, barely notice it.
I love how responsive this powertrain is.
There's no adaptive suspension in this 350H Premium, so changing drive modes doesn't really
do a whole lot except for steering, weight, and throttle response.
Even though it's a much longer and larger car, it doesn't feel difficult or tedious to
place on the road.
It's still narrow enough to fit through small gaps.
Seats are super comfortable, and great visibility from this driving position too.
I don't know if we're going to get a chance to go on the highway with this route, so I
will just kind of sum up some thoughts on that.
The Toyota Safety, or sorry, Lexus Safety Assist 4.0, or whatever it's called, is fine.
It's about the same as it's always been.
The lane centering works well enough, it's not perfect.
The lane change is something I could probably just do without.
You have to keep your hands on the wheel, it does okay.
There's a lot of beeping going on, it's whatever.
Adaptive cruise control, following distance changes are easily made right here, and it's
pretty much the same button layout that we've had in a lot of other Toyota models and Lexus
models but just with this new pad here.
And it seems to work just fine, everything is nicely differentiated, and I like that
I don't have to look up into a head-up display to see what I'm pressing.
Lexus is employing the use of wheel covers now, it's kind of interesting to see those
make a comeback.
When I was growing up, every car had hubcaps, and these are wheel covers for better aerodynamics,
which they're basically hubcaps.
Lexus has three interior options, this Palermo, which looks fantastic, black, and white.
Something that I will note is that there is a built-in dash camera in all Lexus ES's now.
It's hidden, so it's integrated into somewhere up here.
going off pretty much every time I accelerated and hit the brakes so I had
to go into the settings adjust that it was set to normal sensitivity which was
not acting normally at all it was acting like I was just doing some crazy stuff
driving around San Diego and I guess maybe I am a little bit but I don't know
I turned the sensitivity completely off so that it only records when there's an
airbag trigger and I guess you could manually record stuff otherwise or just
tap into a looped recording from your drive it's not the most seamless
integration of a dash cam but I think once you get used to it it's okay there
is this home page where you can go up here and record an event so you can
access that pretty quickly all right we're gonna get back to the resort and
drive some other variants but those are some first impressions on the new Lexus
ES we'll go see what the EV Lexus ES feels like and drives like and we'll
come back to you guys with another video on those driving impressions until then
thank you so much for watching we'll see you in the next one